Guide to the Bob Holman Audio/Video Poetry Collection 1977-2002 MSS.128
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XII: Vinyl Sound Recordings
  - Subseries A: Vinyl Recordings - LPs, 12 in.
    - Ed Sanders, Beer Cans on the Moon; Reprise Records (Box 37)
    - The Fugs, Star Peace; New Rose Records (Box 37)
    - The Fugs, It Crawled Into My Hand, Honest; Reprise Records (Box 37)
    - The Fugs, It Crawled Into My Hand, Honest; Reprise Records (Box 37)
    - Fantasy, Doug E. Fresh and the Get Fresh Crew; Reality Records (Box 37)
    - Grand Master Flash and Furious Five, It's Nasty (Genius of Love); Sugar Hill Records (Box 37)
    - Sugarhill Gang, Rapper's Delight; Sugar Hill Records (Box 37)
    - Sugarhill Gang, Rapper's Delight; Sugar Hill Records (Box 37)
    - Grand Master Flash and the Furious Five Featuring Melle Mel and Duke Bootee, The Message; Sugar Hill Records (Box 37)
    - The Adventures of Grandmaster Flash on the Wheels of Steel/Grandmaster Flash and the Furious Five, The Party Mix; Sugar Hill Records (Box 37)
    - Through the Eyes of Terry Ber, Songs of Terry Ber and Other Poets; World Pacific, a Division of Liberty Records, Inc. (Box 37)
    - Poet Song, Tina and David Meltzer; Vanguard (Box 37)
    - The Best of Mimi and Richard Farina; Vanguard (Box 37)
    - D.J. Wally and Edwin Torres, Rhumba Bomballet/Embroidered Delirium; Kill Rock Stars (Box 37)
    - D.J. Wally and Edwin Torres, Rhumba Bomballet/Embroidered Delirium; Kill Rock Stars (Box 37)
    - The 1969 Warner/Reprise Songbook; Warner Bros. Records, Inc. (Box 37)
    - The Fugs First Album; Base Record (Box 37)
    - The Fugs First Album, Reissue of Broadside BR 304; ESP Disk (Box 37)
    - The Fugs. No More Slavery; New Rose Records (Box 37)
    - The Fugs, 1028; Base Record (Box 37)
    - The Fugs, 1028; ESP Disk (Box 37)
    - Captain Beefheart and the Magic Band, Doc at the Radar Station; Virgin Records, Ltd. (DEACCESSIONED AUGUST 2010) (Box 38)
    - Captain Beefheart and the Magic Band, Unconditionally Guaranteed; Virdin Records, Ltd. (Box 38)
    - Captain Beefheart and the Magic Band, Trout Mask Replica; Straight Records (Box 38)
    - Reflections and Poetry; Silhouette Music (Box 38)
    - Captain Beefheart and the Magic Band, Ice Cream for Crow; Virgin Records, Ltd. (DEACCESSIONED AUGUST 2010) (Box 38)
    - Captain Beefheart and the Magic Band, Clear Spot; Reprise Records (Box 38)
    - Zapped, Bizarre; Reprise Records (Box 38)
    - Zapped, Bizarre; Reprise Records (Box 38)
    - Captain Beefheart and the Magic Band, Grow Fins Volume II: Trout Mask House Sessions 1969; Xeric (Box 38)
    - Captain Beefheart and the Magic Band, Shiny Beast (Bat Chain Puller); Virgin Records, Ltd. (DEACCESSIONED AUGUST 2010) (Box 38)
    - Captain Beefheart and the Magic Band, Bluejeans and Moonbeams; Virgin Records, Ltd. (Box 38)
    - Captain Beefheart and the Magic Band, Safe as Milk; Buddha Records (Box 38)
  - Subseries B: Vinyl Recordings - EPs, 7 in.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Several of the discs in this subseries are currently housed in low quality and/or torn sleeves. The Jill Kroesen "I Really Want to Bomb You" EP disk (fifth from the end of the subseries) is warped.
    - Laurie Anderson, O Superman/Walk the Dog; Warner Bros. Records, Inc. (Box 39)
      Format: Sound Disc: Analog, 33 1/3 rpm; 7 in.
    - Wordcore Volume One: Kathleen Hanna, Rockstar/Slim Moon, Mean; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
      Format: Sound Disc: Analog, [33 1/3] rpm; 7 in.
    - Wordcore Volume One: Kathleen Hanna, Rockstar/Slim Moon, Mean; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume One: Kathleen Hanna, Rockstar/Slim Moon, Mean; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Two: Stacey Levine, Sweethearts Girl /Peter Toliver, Wad Load Boy; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Two: Stacey Levine, Sweethearts Girl /Peter Toliver, Wad Load Boy; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Three: Jean Smith, Carboni Angel; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Three: Jean Smith, Carboni Angel; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Four: Penny Arcade, A Cunt is a Useful Thing!; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Four: Penny Arcade, A Cunt is a Useful Thing!; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Five: She's Good People; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Five: She's Good People; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Six: Peter Plate, History Comes Around Like Snipers on a Rooftop; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Six: Peter Plate, History Comes Around Like Snipers on a Rooftop; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Seven: Exene Cervenka; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Seven: Exene Cervenka; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - KRS Wordcore Volume Eight: Emily KYZ, Jimmy Page Loves Lori Maddox, Sinatra Walks Out; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - KRS Wordcore Volume Eight: Emily KYZ, Jimmy Page Loves Lori Maddox, Sinatra Walks Out; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Nine: Nicole Panter, The Story Lady; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - Wordcore Volume Ten: Billy Chikdish, Hangman Comunication; Kill Rock Stars (Box 39)
    - The Pendulum Floors; Villa Villakula Records (Box 39)
    - Word and Sound with Instruments, Featuring Edwin Torres, Pavel Fajt, Wallace Stevens, KLMR; 715 Records (Box 39)
      Format: Sound Disc: Analog, 45 rpm; 7 in.
    - Jennifer Blowdryer, My Parents Were Beatniks/I Have a Nightclub Pig Inside of Me; 715 Records (Box 39)
    - KLMR-Mali, Edwin Torres-"Mirror-Fuc-Cation, "Wallace Stevens-Bantoms in Pine Woods,Torres-Knoll, E-Loop/Pavel Fajt-1995 Hermit Drum Solo; 715 Records (Box 39)
    - Allen Ginsberg with the Gluons, Birdbrain; Alekos Records (Box 39)
    - Anne Waldman, Uh-Oh Plutonium!; Hyacinth Girls Music (Box 39)
    - Panic DJ's Rock 'n' Roll Mythology/Made in Japan; Words on 45 (Box 39)
      Format: Sound Disc: Analog, [45] rpm; 7 in.
    - Panic DJ's Rock 'n' Roll Mythology/Made in Japan; Words on 45 (Box 39)
      Format: Sound Disc: Analog, [45] rpm; 7 in. The sleeve does not match the disc's label.
    - Bingo Gazingo and the Eigth Grade, "Are You a Lover?" b/w "Juice with Juice;" Holy Plastic (Box 39)
    - Un Cuerpo Exquisito, Te Quiere, Tu Amante Bilinque; Villa Villakula Records (Box 39)
    - Buford Hicks Band, ZZ Queen/Pickup Truck; Prairie Dust Records (Box 39)
    - Lulu Revue, A.W.O.L./ My Place Assassin, Iceland; Zanon Records (Box 39)
    - The Newshounds, The Press Conference; Ragun Records (Box 39)
    - Private Angst; Catheart Records (Box 39)
    - Bazingo Gazingo Loves You So Fucking Much He Can't Shit; Metaphysical Dumping Grounds Records (Box 39)
    - The Stimulators, Loud Fast Rules!/Run Run Run; The Stimulators (Box 39)
    - Didus and the Fabulous Mascarenes, So and So/These Boots Are Made for Walkin'; Xtinct Records (Box 39)
    - Santo, Son of A Working Man/Loisaida; The Source Unltd Records and Tapes (Box 39)
    - Beanie the Singing Dog with the Beanettes, Beanie for Peace; Conscious Decision Records (Box 39)
    - Re-Flex, The Politics of Dancing/Flex It!; Capitol Records (Box 39)
    - The Mighty Imperials, Kick the Bucket/Toothpick; Desco Records (Box 39)
    - Miguel Algarin-"She," Edwin Torres-"equinnical kiss," Sean G. Meehan-"drumset"; Trust (Box 39)
    - Emily XYZ, Who Shot Sadat/The Stripsearch, Hey Kid; InylRepellant (Box 39)
    - Jill Kroesen, I Really Want to Bomb You, Jesus Song; Infidelity (Box 39)
    - The Revolution of Everyday Life, Dos with Denis Mahoney/Black Pig Liberation Front; Pop Rocket Records (Box 39)
    - Doomed #001: Money, Material Takeover/White Lies, Desensitized; Doomed Recordz (Box 39)
    - Knowbody, Love Makes You Vicious; R and R Produtions (Box 39)
    - Essential Logic, Popcorn Boy, Waddle You Do?, Flora Force; Rough Trade and Logic Records (Box 39)
  - Subseries C: Vinyl Recordings - African American
    Scope and Content note
    Items in this subseries reflect original order of Bob Holman.
    - The Last Poets Original from the Hit Movie "Right On!;" Juggernaut Records (Box 40)
    - Sidney Poitier Reads Poetry of the Black Man with Doris Belack, Music by the Brooks Male Chorus; United Artists Records (Box 40)
    - Sidney Poitier Reads Poetry of the Black Man with Doris Belack, Music by the Brooks Male Chorus; United Artists Records (Box 40)
    - Matzoh Balls, Slim and Slam; Caete Records (Box 40)
    - Adventures in Negro History Volume II: The Frederick Douglas Years 1817-1895; Highlight radio Productions (Box 40)
    - Beyond the Blues, American Negro Poetry: Brock Peters, Vinette Carroll, Cleo Laine, and Gordon Heath; Argo (Box 40)
    - Get Your Ass in the Water and Swim Like Me, Narrative Poetry from the Black Oral Tradition; Rounder Records (Box 40)
    - The Poetry of Langston Hughes Read by Ruby Dee and Ossie Davis; Caedmon Records, Ltd. (Box 40)
    - The Last Poets, Oh My People; Celluloid (Box 40)
    - The Last Poets, Time Has Come Sampler; Mercury Records (Box 40)
    - The Last Poets, Time Has Come Sampler; Mercury Records (Box 40)
    - Excerpts from Mouth Almighty's "Flippin' the Script, Rap Meets Poetry;" Mercury Records (Box 40)
    - Roy Hill Reads Poetry From Two Worlds, Recorded Live at Kansas State University, Washburn University, University of Kansas; Audio House (Box 40)
    - Amiri Baraka, Leroi Jones, New Music-New Poetry with David Murray and Steve McCall; India Navigation (Box 40)
    - Jayne Cortez and the Fire-Spitters, There It Is; Bola Press (Box 40)
    - Nicolas Guillen, Poet Laureate of Revolutionary Cuba; Folkways Records (Box 40)
    - Jose Coronel Urtecho, Poesia, Palabra de Esta America; Casa de las Americas (Box 40)
    - Jayne Cortez, Unsbmissive Blues; Bola Press (Box 40)
    - Loose Joints, Poetry by Pedro Pietri; Folkways Records (Box 40)
    - Ornette Coleman, Science Fiction; Columbia Records (Box 40)
    - Imamu Amiri Baraka (Le Roi Jones), The Original Last Poets, Black Spirits: Festival of New Black Poets in America; Black Forum (Box 40)
    - LKJ in Dub; Mango Records (Box 40)
    - Linton Kwesi Johnson, Bass Culture; Mango Records (Box 40)
    - Linton Kwesi Johnson, Dread Beat an' Blood; Virgin Records (Box 40)
    - Linton Kwesi Johnson, Making History; Mango Records (Box 40)
    - Linton Kwesi Johnson, Reggae Reggae Great Greats; Mango Records (Box 40)
    - Linton Kwesi Johnson, Forces of Victory; Mango Records (Box 40)
    - Lillian Allen, Revolutionary Tea Party; Redwood Records (Box 40)
    - Lillian Allen, Conditions Critical; Redwood Records (Box 40)
    - Word Soun' 'Ave Power Reggae Poetry; Heartbeat (Box 40)
    - Woman Talk, Caribbean Dub Poetry; Heartbeat (Box 40)
    - Akabu; Viva Records (Box 40)
    - Michael Smith, "Mi C-YaaN beLieVe iT;" Mango Records (Box 40)
    - Clifton Joseph with the Livestock Band, Oral/Trans/Missions; Verse to Vinyl Records (Box 40)
    - Conjure: Music for the Texts of Ishmael Reed; American Clave (Box 40)
    - The Last Poets, Douglas 3; Douglas Communications (Box 40)
  - Subseries D: Vinyl Recordings - Various Poets
    - Lord Buckley, A Most Immaculately Hip Aritocrat; Straight Records (Box 41)
    - Lord Buckley in Concert; Demon Verbals (Box 41)
    - Lord Buckley, Bad Rapping of the Marquis de Sade in Newly Discovered Live Performances; World Pacific (Box 41)
    - The Sick Humor of Lenny Bruce; Fantasy (Box 41)
    - Lenny Bruce, "I am Not a Nut, Elect Me!; Fantasy (Box 41)
    - The Real Lenny Bruce; Fantasy (Box 41)
    - Lenny Bruce, The Berkeley Concert Two Record Set; Reprise Records (Box 41)
    - Lord Buckley, Blowing His Mind (and Yours Too); World Pacific (Box 41)
    - The Best of Lord Buckley; Elektra (Box 41)
    - Kenneth Patchen Reads His Poetry with the Chamber Jazz Sextet; Cadence (Box 41)
    - Kenneth Rexroth; Fantasy (Box 41)
    - Poetry Readings in the Cellar with the Cellar Jazz Quintet: Kenneth Rexroth, Lawrence Ferlinghetti; Fantasy (Box 41)
    - Douglas Moore, The Devil and Daniel Webster; Westminster Hi-Fi Long Play Records (Box 41)
    - Wilfred Owen (1893-1918), Richard Johnson as Wilfred Owen with Tony Church, Frank Duncan, Edited by Frederick Woods; Argo (Box 41)
    - The Poetry and Voice of James Wright; Caedmon (Box 41)
    - E.E. Cummings Reads His Poetry; Caedmon (Box 41)
    - E.E. Cummings Reads His Poetry; Caedmon (Box 41)
    - The Poetry of Carl Sandberg; Caedmon (Box 41)
    - Robert Frost Reads His Poetry; Caedmon (Box 41)
    - Carl Sandburg Reading Fog and Other Poems; Caedmon (Box 41)
    - Ernest Hemingway Reading; Caedmon (Box 41)
    - T.S. Eliot Reading Poems and Choruses; Caedmon (Box 41)
  - Subseries E: Vinyl Recordings - Allen Ginsberg
    This group of Allen Ginsberg recordings was purchased at an October 1999 Sotheby's auction by Bob Holman.
    - Auction Materials, 1999 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      This folder holds Bob Holman's receipt and invoice from Sotheby's detailing his purchase of the materials in subseries E along with a copy of the auction catalog ("Allen Ginsberg and Friends") and a newspaper clipping regarding the auction: Edward Sanders, "The Beats on the Block," The New York Times, October 3, 1999, p. 17.
    - The John Cooper Clarke Airplay Sampler; CBS Records (Box 42)
    - Barry Wallenstein, Cecil McBee, Stanley Cowell, Beast Is; AK BA Records (Box 42)
    - Krack House; Shimmy Disc (Box 42)
    - Richard Hell and the Voidoids, Blank Generation; Sire (Box 42)
    - You're a Hook, The 15 Year Anniversary of Dial-a-Poem (1968-1983) (Box 42)
    - The Dial-a-Poem Poets, Disconnected; Giorno Poetry Systems (Box 42)
    - Janet Baker and Gerald Moore, A Pageant of English Song (1597-1961); His Master's Voice (Box 42)
    - The Twentieth Anniversary of the Summer of Love; Shimmy Disc (Box 42)
    - Start, Look Around; Fresh Sounds, Inc. (Box 42)
    - Allen Ginsberg, The Lion for Real; Great Jones (Box 42)
    - Ginsberg's Thing; Douglas Recording Corp. (Box 42)
    - A Pause in the Disaster, A Satire of the Conception Corporation; Cotillion (Box 42)
    - Made Up in Texas; Paris Records (Box 42)
    - Allen Ginsberg and Hobo Blues Band, Uvoltes (Howl); Krem (Box 42)
    - Tuli Kupferberg, Tuli and Friends; Shimmy Disc (Box 42)
    - The Clash, Combat Rock; Epic (Box 42)
    - Quarterly; Student Government Association of Montclair State College (Box 42)
    - Robert Johnson, King of the Delta Blues Singers; Columbia Records (Box 42)
    - Songs of Innocence and Experience by William Blake, Tuned by Allen Ginsberg; MGM Records (Box 42)
    - Allen Ginsberg Reads Kaddish, A 20th Century American Ecstatic Narrative Poem; Atlantic (Box 42)
    - Allen Ginsberg, First Blues; John Hammond Records (Box 42)
    - Allen Ginsberg, First Blues; John Hammond Records (Box 42)
    - Allen Ginsberg, First Blues; John Hammond Records (Box 42)
    - The Jack Kerouac Collection; Rhino Records, Inc. (Box 42)
      Format: Audiocassette HX Pro B NR
    - The Jack Kerouac Collection; Rhino Records, Inc. (Box 42)
- Series XIII. 2015 Accretion: Bowery Poetry, 2002-2004; 8.5 Linear Feet in 8 record cartons and 1 flat box
  Arrangement
  This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor, which is primarily chronological.